Alexander W. Tickle

4824 Muir Ave, San Diego, CA 92107 | (619) 736-1039 | alexander.tickle@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-tickle/ | Portfolio: https://alextickle.github.io/

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with strong analytical skills dedicated to building and optimizing creative web applications that provide intuitive user experiences. Strong background in project management from previous professional experience in software localization and wildlife conservation.

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy | San Diego, CA

March 2017 - June 2017

Javascript full stack Javascript web development boot camp – Node, Express, React, PostgreSQL UC San Diego Extension | San Diego, CA

July 2016 - August 2017

Java Programming Certificate Program

University of Pennsylvania | Philadelphia, PA

...,

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA = 3.75/4.0)

2009 - 2013

SKILLS

Languages – Javascript, Java, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML5, Sass

Frameworks/Libraries - React, Express, jQuery, JUnit

Other- Eclipse, Maven, IDLE, gulp, SDL Trados, UI/UX design, Linux, pair programming, agile development, REST API's **PROJECTS**

All source code available on GitHub: https://github.com/alextickle

CrudApp – Java inventory management application with both GUI and command line views to demonstrate MVC architecture. GUI built using Swing components. Data persisted into database using JDBC and PostgreSQL. Built in Eclipse.

Arcade – Express app that serves four arcade-style single page applications: Asteroids, Battleship, Black Jack, and Turtle Graphics. Extensive use of jQuery to update CSS properties of HTML5 elements.

Oregon Trail – Express app modeled after the classic video game. Uses Sequelize and PostgreSQL to persist game data.

Breakfast Club – React app where users can organize weekly breakfast meetups. Express/PostgreSQL backend, makes use of the Yelp API.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MJD Interactive | San Diego, CA

June 2017 – Present

Web Development Intern

- Implemented new features and performed testing/QA on client React application
- 25 pull requests merged into master
- Added browser support for 6 browser/device combinations
- Extensive use of Pivotal Tracker, an agile project management platform

CETRA Language Solutions | San Diego, CA

April 2016 - March 2017

Project Manager

- Managed translation projects from client handoff to final delivery for market research firms
- Communicated directly with clients and vendors to determine project scope, report on progress, and adapt to changes

Local Concept | San Diego, CA

June 2015 – March 2016

Project Coordinator

 Coordinated localization projects of all types (software, user guide documentation, instructional posters, packaging, etc) for Hewlett-Packard, one of Local Concept's largest clients

Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology (MPI-EVA) | Leipzig, Germany

August 2013 - December 2015

Field Site Manager

- Managed temporary field site for chimpanzee research in GEPRENAF zone of northern Côte d'Ivoire as part of MPI-EVA's Pan African Program (comparative study of chimpanzees at 30+ field sites across Africa)
- Responsible for all data collection, logistics, team management, and accounting for entire 15-month study
- Extensive use of handheld GPS, GIS software, and Excel
- Coauthored "Chimpanzee accumulative stone throwing" (manuscript published in Scientific Reports, https://www.nature.com/articles/srep22219)